<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Typogram Blog</title>
    <link href="https://www.typogram.co/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.typogram.co/blog" />
    <updated>2022-04-03T01:28:46-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.typogram.co/blog</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Our Journey to Launching Typogram&#x27;s Pre-order </title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.typogram.co/blog/our-journey-to-launch-typograms-preorder/"/>
        <id>https://www.typogram.co/blog/our-journey-to-launch-typograms-preorder/</id>
            <category term="Startups"/>

        <updated>2022-04-03T01:28:46-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/11/ourJourney.png" alt="we launched typogram" />
                     Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/11/ourJourney.png" alt="we launched typogram" />
                <form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations</em></p>
<p class="align-center"><label for="bd-email">Enter your email</label> <input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form><hr>
<p>Hi There! You might be reading this because we just launched our preorder page for our app, <a href="https://www.typogram.co/">Typogram</a>. Typogram is a design tool that we have been working on. Specifically, it’s a beginner-friendly logo design and editing tool for non-designers. <strong><em>Today, we are launching our pre-order. We are offering one brand lifetime license for $49.99, at 60% discount. You can create your brand inside our app and update it forever.</em></strong></p>
<figure class="post__video"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="314" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7PHHaLh1zNU" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></figure>
<h2>Why did we launch this? </h2>
<p>First of all, a brief introduction: We are Hua and Wenting, and we are the makers behind this app. Before Typogram, we have collaborated on several other projects, like<a href="https://typogram.github.io/Anicons/"> Anicons.</a></p>
<p>We are both passionate designers that want to create easy-to-use design tools that enable people to feel fun and creative. We want to make design more accessible for non-designers. This launch is a special milestone because Typogram has been an idea in the works for a long time. We wanted to share our journey to this point so far.  </p>
<h2>What was the start of Typogram?</h2>
<p>Typogram started out as a professional tool for designers in its earliest stage. As we ran around with equipment and interviewed users, we realized that this app better served non-designers. We had met many newly minted business owners looking to launch their product with a presentable, eye-catching website branded with marketing and a unique logo. They needed their logos designed but didn’t know who to turn to. Many ended up designing logos themselves and complained about the lack of learning resources and an easy-to-use, beginner-friendly tool, geared especially for non-designers to design logos. </p>
<p>After hearing about this pain point, we put our heads down to work by creating free design education resources for entrepreneurs, like<a href="https://fontdiscovery.typogram.co/"> FontDiscovery</a>, doing<a href="https://workshop.typogram.co/#about"> workshops</a> at accelerators like Yale’s<a href="https://city.yale.edu/"> Tsai City</a>, and co-working spaces, like<a href="https://www.the-wing.com/"> the Wing</a>. In addition, we made mini design tools, like<a href="https://www.codingfont.com/"> Coding Font</a>.  </p>
<p>We also developed our features quickly using no-code tools and tested out our app with an initial group of customers. We brought users on-site, had them test out our apps, nervously observed their interactions with our app. When the pandemic hit, we user tested remotely. Eventually, we figured out what worked, what didn’t and built out the features with code! Our customers were happy with what we have and paid us.</p>
<h2>What was the most challenging part of this launch? </h2>
<p>As shy creatives and engineers, the most challenging aspect of this launch had two layers. First, putting ourselves out there in many unexpected ways, and second, internalized pressure of launching and the desire to be perfect. This was a massive project for us and required us to put ourselves out there consistently. An example is the making of landing page marketing and our product video. We wrote the script, recorded and edited ourselves as the audio, and assembled the footage with in-app recordings and self-made animations. Every single aspect challenged us to do something out of our comfort zone. We were lucky to have a supportive community and friends that challenged us every step of the way.</p>
<p>Now that we feel more confident because our closed alpha customers were satisfied, we are ready to show everyone what we got! That brings us to this preorder launch. We are looking to share more about this journey as we go, all the ups and downs. </p>
<h2>How can I support? </h2>
<p>Launching a business is hard –– It would mean a lot to us if you could support us!</p>
<p><em><strong>The best way to support is through pre-ordering our product. Right now, it is offered at $49.99, a 60% discount, for a one brand lifetime license. This means that you can create your brand make updates to it forever as soon as we launch.  </strong></em></p>
<h3>Don't need Typogram?</h3>
<p>You can also help us by... </p>
<ul>
<li>Follow us on<a href="https://twitter.com/typogramco"> Twitter</a>! Tell your friends about us or tweet about us.</li>
<li>Subscribe to our newsletters:<a href="https://build.typogram.co/"> Build-in-public updates</a> &amp;<a href="https://fontdiscovery.typogram.co/"> FontDiscovery.</a></li>
<li>If you are Podcaster or Youtuber, consider interviewing us? </li>
<li>Are you a Blogger? Maybe we can do a guest blog? </li>
<li>Thank you so much! It means a lot to small indie business owners like us!</li>
</ul>
<hr><form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow">
<p><em>If you enjoyed this post, subscribe to get updates from our blog! </em></p>
<p class="align-center"><label for="bd-email">Enter your email</label> <input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Essential Typography Terms You Must Know to Boost Your Design Skills, Part 1</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.typogram.co/blog/essential-typography-terms-you-must-know-to-boost-your-design-skills-part-1/"/>
        <id>https://www.typogram.co/blog/essential-typography-terms-you-must-know-to-boost-your-design-skills-part-1/</id>
            <category term="Typography &amp; Fonts"/>
            <category term="Branding"/>

        <updated>2022-04-01T01:11:10-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/new_blogPost5PresentationCover_2.png" alt="" />
                     Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/new_blogPost5PresentationCover_2.png" alt="" />
                <form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><label for="bd-email">Enter your email</label> <input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>

<hr>
<h3 id="typography">Typography</h3>
<p>Art of arranging pieces of text via typefaces to make information legible, readable and pleasing to the eye.</p>
<h3 id="typeface">Typeface</h3>
<p>A typeface is a set of glyphs or characters like (alphabet) that share a common design. For example, Helvetica</p>
<h3 id="font">Font</h3>
<p>A font was a particular size, weight and style of a typeface. For example, 12 point Helvetica bold.</p>
<h3 id="font-family">Font Family</h3>
<p>A set of fonts that shared design styles. For example, Helvetica Bold and Helvetica Regular, both of these are in the Helvetica Family.</p>
<h3 id="font-weight">Font Weight</h3>
<p>The weight of a particular font is the thickness of the character relative to their height.</p>
<h3 id="font-style">Font Style</h3>
<p>Normal, italicized, oblique style of the font.</p>
<p><strong>Normal</strong> </p>
<ul>
<li>Also called Roman, where the text is upright.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Italic</strong></p>
<p>Italicized and oblique are both ways to create a slant typeface(usually for emphasis).</p>
<ul>
<li>A true italic font is cursive and slanted.
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/italic.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/responsive/italic-xs.png 300w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/responsive/italic-sm.png 480w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/responsive/italic-md.png 768w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/responsive/italic-lg.png 1024w"  alt="trueItalic" width="1848" height="924" /></figure></li>
</ul>
<p>img: a true italic has little curved tails around its letters, signaling its a cursive. True italic works well, even better for emphasis, so if the font you are using has both “italic” and “oblique”, use italic!</p>
<p><strong>Oblique</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Another way to create a slant typeface. An italic font slants slightly to the right.
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/oblique.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/responsive/oblique-xs.png 300w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/responsive/oblique-sm.png 480w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/responsive/oblique-md.png 768w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/9/responsive/oblique-lg.png 1024w"  alt="oblicqueItalic" width="1848" height="924" /></figure></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Create a Stellar Pitch Presentation with These Five Tips</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.typogram.co/blog/business-pitch-presentation-design-tips/"/>
        <id>https://www.typogram.co/blog/business-pitch-presentation-design-tips/</id>
            <category term="Branding"/>

        <updated>2022-03-31T02:12:56-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/new_blogPost5PresentationCover.png" alt="" />
                     Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/new_blogPost5PresentationCover.png" alt="" />
                <form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><label for="bd-email">Enter your email</label> <input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>

<hr>
<h1 id="presentation-counts">Presentation Counts</h1>
<p>There are many types of presentations. This article primarily addresses pitch presentations since there is a significant focus on storytelling. The tips here can be helpful for other types of presentations as well. Consistent design and compelling storytelling can play a huge role in creating a powerful presentation.</p>
<p><strong>These five rules can be good starting points:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Use images to tells a story</li>
<li>Use appropriate fonts</li>
<li>Add white space and be concise</li>
<li>Use scale to help with delivery</li>
<li>Create lasting impression by being consistent visually</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Remember, presentation is storytelling. When you design a presentation, you are using visual language as a tool to tell the story.</strong></p>
<hr>
<h1 id="use-images-to-tells-a-story">Use images to tells a story</h1>
<p>A picture is worth a thousand words. Ask yourself these questions: </p>
<ul>
<li>What is the story of your presentation?</li>
<li>What message or emotion do you want to leave the audience with?</li>
<li>How can this specific slide help you in getting that message across?</li>
<li>How can the image on that particular slide maximize this role?</li>
</ul>
<p>Once you figure out these questions, start searching for images. images that tell story about processes, illustrate pivotal moments, and associate with specific emotions are particularly helpful to presentations. If you want to learn more about how to visualize ideas, check out this <a href="https://www.typogram.co/blog/small-business-marketing-ideas/">post</a>.</p>
<p>A good tactic is using full bleed (edge to edge) images to illustrating pivotal moments, visions, impressive examples. It is more effective if the images are in high resolution.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/blogPost5Presentation1.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation1-xs.png 300w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation1-sm.png 480w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation1-md.png 768w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation1-lg.png 1024w"  alt="leftCentervsFullBleed" width="2024" height="1012" /></figure></p>
<p>img: left- centered image on a slide; right- full bleed image. The full bleed image on the right will usually work better than on the left. It pulls in the audience a lot more since it is bigger in scale.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="use-appropriate-fonts">Use appropriate fonts</h1>
<p>If you have a brand typography system, this can be an excellent place to use it. If you don’t know what font to use, choose Helvetica or a neutral serif, like <a href="https://fontdiscovery.typogram.co/p/fontdiscovery-13-plex-a-font-family">Plex Sans</a> or <a href="https://fontdiscovery.typogram.co/p/fow-no4-libre-franklin-a-versatile?s=w">Libre Franklin</a>.</p>
<p>When you do a presentation, you want people to take you seriously. Display fonts generally are too decorative and distracting to use in a formal setting. You probably want to save your scripts and handwriting fonts for the presentation most of the time.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/blogPost5Presentation2.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation2-xs.png 300w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation2-sm.png 480w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation2-md.png 768w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation2-lg.png 1024w"  alt="appropriateFont" width="2024" height="1012" /></figure></p>
<p>img: left- handwriting font is not appropriate for formal presentation. right- a fairly neutral sans serif is better suited and more clear.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="improve-readability-by-adding-white-space">Improve readability by adding white space</h1>
<p>When you are creating a presentation, you are presenting a body of information clearly to your audience. An effective presentation is concise. This means shorter sentences, less text, and more white space. Considering adding space:</p>
<ul>
<li>Between lines of text</li>
<li>Between bullet point and text</li>
<li>Between bullet point and bullet point</li>
</ul>
<p>If your text can breathe, the reader’s eyes can breathe.</p>
<p>If a reader’s eyes can breathe, they will have an easier time understand and remember your story.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/blogPost5Presentation3.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation3-xs.png 300w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation3-sm.png 480w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation3-md.png 768w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation3-lg.png 1024w"  alt="InformationWhitespace" width="2024" height="1012" /></figure></p>
<p>img: left- too much information and overcrowding. right- concise information with lots of white space create better readability.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="use-scale-to-help-with-delivery">Use scale to help with delivery</h1>
<p>Scale is one of the most effective tools you can use to create dramatic visual imageries. If you want to emphasize a statement, consider making the sentence bigger on a separate slide because this creates anticipation and grabs attention. It is like a punch line.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/blogPost5Presentation4.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation4-xs.png 300w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation4-sm.png 480w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation4-md.png 768w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/8/responsive/blogPost5Presentation4-lg.png 1024w"  alt="typographyHierachy" width="2024" height="1012" /></figure></p>
<p>img: bigger text feels more impactful to audience.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="create-lasting-impression-by-being-consistent-visually">Create lasting impression by being consistent visually</h1>
<p>In the end, your presentation is a visual document that tells a story about your ideas. The way it looks is the method you use to tell the story.</p>
<p>When I make a presentation, I try to be consistent with how I show(design) the information on each slide. This means:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use the same fonts for header and body texts.</li>
<li>Keep the spacing between texts consistent.</li>
<li>Keep track of all the different sizes of text you are using and stay consistent with text sizes between different levels of information.</li>
</ul>
<p>Consistency will erase lots of needless frictions in your presentation, which will create more effective, straightforward storytelling.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="phew-that-was-it">Phew. That was it.</h1>
<p>I hope this is helpful if you need to fundraise, or create presentations for work. Presentation is storytelling. If you master this well, it is a powerful skill that translates into many other areas.</p>
<form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Mood Board 101: How Do Small Businesses Design and Create Marketing ideas?</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.typogram.co/blog/small-business-marketing-ideas/"/>
        <id>https://www.typogram.co/blog/small-business-marketing-ideas/</id>
            <category term="Branding"/>

        <updated>2022-03-31T02:13:02-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/7/brandingCover-2.png" alt="visualize branding ideas " />
                     Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/7/brandingCover-2.png" alt="visualize branding ideas " />
                <form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><label for="bd-email">Enter your email</label> <input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>

<hr>
<blockquote>
<p>Hi, I am trying to design branding and marketing for my small business. 
How do I get started?  I don’t have any ideas.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="initialize-your-ideas-and-turn-them-into-visuals">Initialize your ideas and turn them into visuals</h2>
<p>You have ideas. You just don’t know the best way to visualize it. Most of the time, when I visualize ideas, I start by writing things down.</p>
<p>If it is my brand, the first thing I write down a mission or vision statement, then I write down a list of adjectives associated with this statement.</p>
<p>For example, at Typogram, our statement is “empower everyone with design and creativity.”</p>
<p><strong>First, I will write a couple of values that I want my brand to project to my customers visually.</strong></p>
<p><em>Empowering, Creative, Fun</em></p>
<p><strong>Then, I can go on Pinterest or any image discovery platform and start pulling together some images to create mood boards.</strong> Lots of people tend to skip this step, but it is super important. Building a mood board helps you build a style/ aesthetic library in your computer and mentally. I know it sounds a little magical, but it’s true. By making a mood board, you will better imagine what your brand can become, visually.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="discover-and-expand-your-visuals">Discover and expand your visuals</h2>
<p>How do we build a mood board from each word? </p>
<p>Consider each word from different angles (customer side, the business side, and so on).</p>
<p><strong>Take the word <em>empowering</em>,  for example:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>What are some emotions associated with empowering?  Maybe Serious? Happiness? Warmth?</li>
<li>What are actions associated with empowering?  Maybe Protest? Diversity? Inclusion? Support Groups?</li>
</ul>
<p>Search on these terms on Pinterest and see what kind of images will come up.</p>
<p><strong>You might see:</strong></p>
<p><em>Serious</em> → dark colors?</p>
<p><em>Happiness</em> → pictures of smiling people,</p>
<p><em>Warmth</em> → sunshine? Yellow, orange, warm colors?</p>
<p><em>Protest</em> → protest poster art, bold fonts</p>
<p>It could be images of people displaying emotions, landscapes, a specific texture, a particular color, a particular event that resonates with you. Choose the images you like and try to pin down the reason you choose a specific image.</p>
<p>You can do this for a few terms. It’s good to have a collection of images (more than 20) for each board. That way, you can identify a running theme among images of within a board, like colors, styles, or aesthetics. This will give you some directions on color palettes, or look and feel of your brand.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="collect-inspirations-and-turn-them-into-value">Collect inspirations and turn them into value</h2>
<p>Mood boards are an excellent resource for inspiration. In addition, it can serve as a collection of resources for your other visual content, such as blog posts, newsletter graphics, or social media posts. It is also a great reference document to hand off to a freelancer or an agency if you are working with one. When I worked at an agency, we feel relieved when clients give us mood boards because it shows us what they are thinking.</p>
<p>Of course, this is my process. You can always do something different that works for you!</p>
<form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Nine Branding &amp; Design Terms Startup Founders Should Know</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.typogram.co/blog/essential-branding-and-design-terms-startup-founders-should-know/"/>
        <id>https://www.typogram.co/blog/essential-branding-and-design-terms-startup-founders-should-know/</id>
            <category term="Branding"/>

        <updated>2022-03-31T02:13:11-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/BrandingTermsCover.png" alt="" />
                     Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/BrandingTermsCover.png" alt="" />
                <form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><label for="bd-email">Enter your email</label> <input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>

<hr>
<p>When you design your brand, it may be helpful to know some key concepts. Here is a list of relevant terms and ideas for branding and design that could be helpful as you work through your design and marketing projects.</p>
<h2 id="brand-identity">Brand Identity</h2>
<p>Brand identity is the visual aspect of a brand. Brand identity includes your logo, imagery, typography, colors, and creative assets. Together, these elements make your brand recognizable to your customers. Your brand identity is one of the most important parts when it comes to creating your brand.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/brandIdentity.gif" alt="Brand Identity" width="1600" height="796" /></figure></p>
<h2 id="logo">Logo</h2>
<p>The logo is the piece of artwork that represents your brand. While a logo is only a single piece of artwork, it is used everywhere on your brand, like landing pages, social media for marketing, and ads. That’s why when you create your logo, you should think about its usability in different environments. There are times when you may have to display your logo in a small size. There might be times when your logo will end up in a dark background. Keeping those restrictions in mind at the beginning will save you troubles later on.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/logo.gif" alt="Logo" width="1600" height="796" /></figure></p>
<h2 id="brand-color">Brand Color</h2>
<p>Brand color is the primary color associated with your brand. It can be on logos, business cards, decks, social media posts, websites, and other branding materials.</p>
<p>It’s also the color your audience will associate your brand with. For example, Home Depot’s brand color is orange.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/brandColor.gif" alt="Brand Color" width="1600" height="796" /></figure></p>
<h2 id="white-spacenegative-space">White Space/Negative Space</h2>
<p>White space, also called negative space, is the area that is left empty in design. It could be around the content or artwork(like a photo),  inside the content, or in-between two pieces of content. White space is crucial because it gives the elements in your design breathing room and provides ease for the viewer when they look at the information. Good use of white space also guides the audience’s eyes from one piece of content to the next, creating a hierarchy of information.</p>
<h2 id="positive-space">Positive Space</h2>
<p>Positive space is the counterpart of negative space. The positive space is the space that the subject (this can be the content, or artwork) takes up.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/twitterNegativePositve.gif" alt="Positive Space" width="2222" height="1108" /></figure></p>
<h2 id="design-composition">Design Composition</h2>
<p>Design composition is how design elements are placed on a page. Since elements are positive space and the unused space is negative space, we can also say that composition is the overall distribution of positive and negative spaces in the design.</p>
<p>A general rule for creating good composition is to find balance between negative and positive space. When there is a lack of balance between negative and positive, there is tension. However, tension can also be explored to create powerful compositions. </p>
<h2 id="design-grid">Design Grid</h2>
<p>Grids in design are systems for creating and organizing layouts. The layouts can be for print or screen. In design, “form follows function,” and layout is the perfect example of this. Different grids(layouts) suit different purposes.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/twitterDesignGrids.gif" alt="Design Grid" width="2222" height="1108" /></figure></p>
<p>img: Different grids have different uses. </p>
<h2 id="typography-system">Typography System</h2>
<p>Typography System is the combination of fonts and font styles that create your visual branding system. For example, you typically have corresponding fonts and font styles for headers, subheads, and body copy on the landing page. For branding, we will normally use the same typography system across most of the branding assets to create a consistent message.</p>
<h2 id="typographic-hierarchy">Typographic Hierarchy</h2>
<p>Typographic hierarchy is the visual cue of scale and spatial relationship between the specific font styles. Typography hierarchy is crucial. It shows the audience which information is the most important and which is the least. For example, on your landing page, you probably want to capture the customers’ attention by first guiding them to the product’s unique value, then offer them a detailed description.</p>
<p>To achieve this visually, you can make the header containing the copy for values of the product to be bigger and bolder in style than the detailed description of the product. That way, the eyes traveled to the header first, then to the description of the project.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/typographySystem.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/responsive/typographySystem-xs.png 300w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/responsive/typographySystem-sm.png 480w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/responsive/typographySystem-md.png 768w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/responsive/typographySystem-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Typography System" width="2024" height="1012" /></figure></p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/typographyHierachy.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/responsive/typographyHierachy-xs.png 300w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/responsive/typographyHierachy-sm.png 480w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/responsive/typographyHierachy-md.png 768w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/6/responsive/typographyHierachy-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Typography Hierachy" width="2024" height="1012" /></figure></p>
<p>img: Information hierarchy is establish through scale relationship using fonts and font pairing.</p>
<p><strong>Hopefully these can help you as you work on design projects for your startup!</strong> </p>
<hr>
<p>Do you have any additional questions or suggestions?  Let me know via Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/typogramco">@typogramco</a></p>
<form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>What is Branding &amp; How Can I Use It for My Startup? </title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.typogram.co/blog/startup-branding/"/>
        <id>https://www.typogram.co/blog/startup-branding/</id>
            <category term="Branding"/>

        <updated>2022-03-31T02:13:16-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/5/whyBrandingCover.png" alt="" />
                     Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/5/whyBrandingCover.png" alt="" />
                <form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><label for="bd-email">Enter your email</label> <input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>
---

<h1 id="why-branding">Why Branding?</h1>
<p>In the sea of savvy digital companies nowadays, it is more important than ever to stand out.</p>
<p>You might be thinking, “well, if I have a super awesome product, do I even need a brand?”</p>
<p><strong>I agree with you! sort of.</strong> </p>
<p>While having a great product that meets the customer’s needs is the most crucial aspect of your business, branding doesn’t hurt. If done well, branding can help to add trust and build relationships between you and your customers.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-branding">What is Branding?</h1>
<p>Branding is not about you. It’s about your customers: how they feel and what they say about your product.</p>
<p>To have good branding, you can think about:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Who are you trying to reach?</strong></li>
<li><strong>How do you want to come across to your customers?</strong>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/5/whyBranding.gif" alt="Image description" width="1206" height="600" /></figure></li>
</ol>
<p>img: who are your customers? and how will your brand come across to them?</p>
<p><strong>Both questions will require you to understand:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>the problem you are trying to solve</li>
<li>the unique value you bring to your customers</li>
<li>good knowledge of the products that are already in your field</li>
</ul>
<p>Answers from these two questions can be the guiding light for you to visualize your brand. You can answer the first question by researching your customers. The second question you can answer by using what you know about your customers and communicating your product’s unique values.</p>
<h1 id="brand-identity-system">Brand Identity System</h1>
<p>Creative collaterals like logos, brand color, brand typeface are known as brand identity systems. The brand identity system is one of the essential parts of the branding process. It helps you think creatively and intentionally about communicating your brand visually to your customers while setting up a visual system for your brand message to stay consistent, trustworthy, and memorable.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/5/uber-4.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/5/responsive/uber-4-xs.png 300w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/5/responsive/uber-4-sm.png 480w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/5/responsive/uber-4-md.png 768w ,https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/5/responsive/uber-4-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Image description" width="2000" height="1125" /></figure></p>
<hr>
<p>Do you have any additional questions or suggestions?  Let me know via Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/typogramco">@typogramco</a></p>
<form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How to Choose Branding Color Palettes for Your Startup</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.typogram.co/blog/how-to-choose-branding-color-palette/"/>
        <id>https://www.typogram.co/blog/how-to-choose-branding-color-palette/</id>
            <category term="Branding"/>

        <updated>2022-03-31T02:55:54-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/4/colorGuideCover.png" alt="How to Choose Branding Color Palettes for Your Business" />
                     Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.typogram.co/blog/media/posts/4/colorGuideCover.png" alt="How to Choose Branding Color Palettes for Your Business" />
                <form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><label for="bd-email">Enter your email</label> <input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>

<hr>
<h1 id="colors-in-art-history">Colors in Art History</h1>
<p>Color is one of the essential elements in art and design. Throughout history, it has been used to depict emotions, delight audiences, and change how we see the world. Artist Pablo Picasso used different colors intentionally and exclusively to express feelings. Painter Paul Cezanne led the Post-Impressionist art movement by reinventing how color is used in landscape paintings.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/Fzj9dg_qsjSq9StT_ar5uEuROdk007kgidxAa_uwzwT0pqhtmXjuQCwkJnsmWKf5H3qryhnX-UjnSvKCwD8aGNyGbdkV1YSPJHGesVuMDbZzS-h5JEAAeMSZyEmZgFbeUevH8CgY=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="paulCezzaneColorUse" /></figure></p>
<p>img: Paul Cezanne’s impressionist landscape paintings had a revolutionary way of using color. Source: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_C%C3%A9zanne">wikipedia</a></p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/Dc_rOIpiJbTTlahhauGgh0Dg-a3BdwBC9BTuCecvgUfpDgkYWnhA86B9k3qaa4HrZ9DRvCJBVvHHLuCLDWL6wMiI1HfmIMKu-jlhBUjZp2EZrnANIdW9y6drO4JcArSDSumG_ZX4=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="PicassonColorUse" /></figure></p>
<p>img: left–Picasso’s blue period; right–Picasso’s rose period; Source: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pablo_Picasso">wikipedia</a> </p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/vnK1dSfd8J6Ni_KsvEwr1_pR67dx_5ArlX3v4kd_fXfN7B3TLFHDutp9jSYi5VN3RJp7IU2Wb7yKNtO2xmX08dhjGD9LsA_RN37ELtUIflyrDoKEPGt-Vld2PUQaznIqn5lsDXjb=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="YvesKleinColorUse" /></figure></p>
<p>img: Artist Yves Klein invented his own shade of blue called <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/International_Klein_Blue">IK Blue.</a> Many brands later started using this blue and It became a popular fashion trend. Source: <a href="https://www.invaluable.com/">invaluable</a></p>
<p>If it hasn’t crossed your mind, different colors have different meanings. Whether it’s landing pages, products, branding, social posts, choosing and using colors effectively can help your audience recognize and remember your brand.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="primary-branding-color">Primary Branding Color</h1>
<h2 id="what-is-a-primary-color">What is a primary color?</h2>
<p>Primary color is the main color that is used on marketing graphics, website, signage. Typically, this is the main color that is associated with your brand. For example, the primary brand color for Coca cola is red.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/pXDOlFKHsgDpJgBZorhNIy3wLXjtP2GsGSFLFpJag_ZOoIdR1IGSfdgSIo-JLxZWXwdCnj4dpncAbG6LQ7Jlxu4hM_Dk8vpNrwLhoOzSR0ygcvshWaUL43AKiZkQfvxShWKRe2Ud=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="cocaColaBrand" /></figure></p>
<p>img: you will find this classic red in alot of coca cola’s branding. Source: <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/3043308/coke-experiments-with-new-universal-branding">Fastco</a> </p>
<h2 id="how-do-you-find-the-right-color">How do you find the right color?</h2>
<p>You can find the right colors through research color palette usage and inspirations. There are a couple of approaches you can take:</p>
<ol>
<li>Look at what similar brands in your niche are doing.</li>
<li>Research about what values colors are associated with.</li>
<li>Create mood boards of things or values inspired or associated with your brand. I wrote more about this process <a href="https://blog.typogram.co/How-to-Visualize-Ideas-for-Your-Brand-ffad9dc7d0704bfb8e45f23db4c420a9">here.</a> You can then sample colors from images in your mood boards.</li>
</ol>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/DrfmgNzxb2FOPF4AoSqvGyZgOJQjYPjTeqr_UYomKDk_rq2ukmx9niDihwtJsNjwDrkINbB6FnFgn9ix8c3LMQwUu3gwxHdy8dFQBMU5iT49F6xyTeCHq8YBC1-NkUNpbjJJXj_t=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="colorthemeInspirationChart" /></figure></p>
<p>img: a simple chart I made of colors with their common associations.</p>
<p>Once you find a color that resonates, it is essential to test it in the environments you will be using. You also want to test how this specific color performs on black and white backgrounds. This test tells you if the color you are using is too vibrant or too dark. You want to make sure it is legible and visible. If you are using it in product packaging, test it out printed. Checking colors is simple, and it saves you time down the line.</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="secondary-color">Secondary Color</h1>
<p>Some brands have a few colors they use consistently along with the primary brand color. These colors are called secondary colors. A secondary color is not a requirement for branding. However, it is nice to have to highlight or complement a primary color. It provides more ways to add recognition and distinguishment to your brands. While there isn’t a rule on how many secondary colors you can have, you should try to limit yourself to about three or four so the brand remains recognizable, and the message remains clear. Having too many colors can be distracting and confusing. You should always use one color as the primary.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/jtbBYGaiGSjHfFFAS_F0XmEUyKhuhZw-B9zRMQkaVvy5wYLDKuyTSf2_1CtnayMnSKWQCa66L2Tp1Kba-ezKBasEWgGd1bnuaNk3Hm2RrM4n5dGqyzI3GX-dduKMDHIffdi37aUa=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="iKeaColorPalette" /></figure></p>
<p>img: Ikea’s color palettes using blue as the primary color, yellow as as secondary color; source: dazeen</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/Djzv2gbDHu8dlVoLWbuyaBM7XqhLx39_X21Nj5EKZr4HcHWjcx1Y43HLu8YFC5YcxBmvAr0-5MHRavBikazN19q39HW9gS7_k5YlQv4wr8R4gHmGTnHsKGF2ekgmM6gQN8IJQrxB=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="mcDonaldColorPalette" /></figure></p>
<p>img: McDonald’s color palettes using red as the primary color, yellow as as secondary color; source: <a href="https://adage.com/creativity/work/mcdonalds-new-visual-identity/2184596">AdAge</a> </p>
<h2 id="how-to-pick-a-secondary-color">How to pick a secondary color?</h2>
<p>There are several ways you can pick your secondary colors.</p>
<p>As a starting point, you can think about:</p>
<ul>
<li>Is there another color you liked when you picked the primary color?</li>
<li>Is there a color that pairs well with the primary color?</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="color-pairing">Color Pairing</h2>
<p>Combining color can be tricky. Consider these ideas when you are combining color for your projects.</p>
<h3 id="monochrome">Monochrome</h3>
<p>You can get various shades of a color by playing with the saturation and lightness of a color.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/WHmzHADixZdDvUTf3BWuuPLM2G4Ft8jM6iufvFWA2MuDPQz5A8Kgnx8sAxZRZBch6k9fXHbO8DWkOUViZZFHhLG5G2vd0TF1F_hgKYUX6eLDHWDqFhtnLJo4stmMQwQ02CKjvijm=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="monoChromeWebDesign" /></figure></p>
<p>img: monochrome web design; source: <a href="https://onextrapixel.com/40-beautiful-examples-of-monochromatic-website-design/">onextrapixel</a></p>
<h3 id="accent">Accent</h3>
<p>An accent color is a color used in small amounts to highlight or add visual punch to the primary color. An accent color is usually a bright color.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/ogNlqNf-tSWok-Mf1qNtgpT-A9Ebm3FbcaLGd_nkzc7vAo8fJ-FrPeEV2vM9Ml77NwseIfYhztsafuMGI0lv9RwKvYLiCSqCJuiU9DhA9Mi4_K9cJaAm5xmxT3HiS7gci3v42Thn=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="accentWebDesign" /></figure></p>
<p>img: light yellow is  used as an accent color in this Nike packaging; source: <a href="https://nirvanacph.com/project/nikegreenspeed/">NirvanaCph</a></p>
<h3 id="grayscale">Grayscale</h3>
<p>Grayscale is the range of shades of gray. The highest level of grayscale is black, and the lightest level is white. Grayscale is useful because gray shades work well as complementary colors and make the colors pop.</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/FXYJuqMCXaIRkjGOmlv5ZSpEmH6ZS2h_quKKN_YUgAiieD5G4iTYfAIRzobhIdStJughYLWh6tFftxdftrX7oq_fgLsW4VkAcSESCb86tIoaUtlO78vzqiG5jHBDwWwn6Hdfwhu2=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="greyscaleWebDesign" /></figure></p>
<p>img: greyscale is used in this museum website; source: <a href="https://www.inselhombroich.de/de">inselhombroich</a></p>
<hr>
<h1 id="additional-tips">Additional Tips</h1>
<h2 id="1-stick-to-your-logo-colors">1. Stick to your logo colors</h2>
<h3 id="do">Do</h3>
<p>Having a primary color people associate with your brand is a good idea.</p>
<h3 id="dont">Don’t</h3>
<p>change your brand colors</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/G53B_2x_XJoz8_hhosoqJTRbxFxOBprMMKB5A_ZRlcecEOBgkDZFZ6l4gay-uCUX86lqFI-5c3N9MK65iFIilmm9DrKO_OYsJUriLrpPNJApbMCi-BsNI7PRBBW61lCeb52QfjWi=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="doanddontofBrandColors" /></figure></p>
<p>img: do and don’t for logo color</p>
<h2 id="2-make-up-a-system-for-using-colors--stick-to-it">2. Make up a system for using colors &amp; stick to it</h2>
<h3 id="do-1">Do</h3>
<p>Be consistent about which colors to use and for what</p>
<h3 id="dont-1">Don’t</h3>
<p>Wing it- use colors randomly and have no rules</p>
<p><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/jXVESRUyXaymh4vL8a8T__o7dZ9x-P_gYsLvgc5EfBmylngveXalFUOIIb8koNH687MMHNn6f5XybCD1Qzxl0-DHO68HFsG_OYH4YrIGweCLH_ckO3fTqL9jQFpSuYy97fhWIBx4=s0" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="doanddontofBrandColors2" /></figure></p>
<p>img: do and don’t for color usage</p>
<hr>
<p>And that’s it for our guide on choosing colors! Do you have any additional questions or suggestions?  Let me know via Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/typogramco">@typogramco</a></p>
<form class="embeddable-buttondown-form" action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow" align = "center">
<p><em>Subscribe to get updates from our blog for doses of design tips and inspirations!</em></p>
<p><input id="bd-email" name="email" type="email"> <input type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form>

            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
