<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Typogram Blog</title>
    <link href="https://typogram.co/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://typogram.co/blog" />
    <updated>2023-09-28T03:38:23-04:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://typogram.co/blog</id>

    <entry>
        <title>How to Start and Grow a Business Without Money</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://typogram.co/blog/how-to-start-and-grow-a-business-without-money/"/>
        <id>https://typogram.co/blog/how-to-start-and-grow-a-business-without-money/</id>
            <category term="Startups"/>
            <category term="Inside Typogram"/>

        <updated>2023-09-28T03:38:23-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/bootsrapperguide_cover-2.png" alt="" />
                    Background Before we start, I would like to give you some background&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/bootsrapperguide_cover-2.png" alt="" />
                <h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Background </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before we start, I would like to give you some background about me and my startup.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My name is Hua Shu, and together with my co-founder, <a href="https://build.typogram.co/" title="Wenting Zhang" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wenting Zhang</a>, we are building a logo design tool for founders called Typogram. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typogram Timeline Snapshot</span></h3>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">2021-  customer discovery, product research, newsletters/content developments </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">2022 - preorder landing page launch </span></li>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">2023 - public alpha launch </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We launched a landing page pre-order for Typogram in March 2022 and a public launch in April 2023. Before that, we did a lot of customer discovery, product development, and user testing. So far, we have crossed 1,500 registered users and generated over $5,000 from Lifetime deals, primarily through organic channels.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In this post, I want to share some frugal methods that worked for product validation and growth. </span></p>
<hr>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">MVP and Product Validation </span></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strategy No.1: Simplified No-Code Version of Feature<br><br></span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are a tiny, two-people, and bootstrapped team. Our resources, such as money, time, knowledge, motivation, and productivity, are limited. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Early in our product development process, we wanted to ensure we could monetize the features. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To test this quickly, we made one of our core features, "identifying brand personality," into a mini product, a workshop kit with no-code tools. No code tools are also popular with users in our niche. This </span><a href="https://typogram.co/workshop"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brand Personality Workshop Kit</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is structured like a workbook with instructions and actionable for participants. Depending on the capabilities of specific no-code platforms, we even intimated what we were thinking for user experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During this time, we also started writing </span><a href="https://build.typogram.co/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">newsletters</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for our audience (see the newsletter section). We launched our mini product on Gumroad and in our newsletters to see if anyone would pay. In the end, we got a couple of customers, which was enough of a quick validation for us for this app feature. </span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/ixMcR-jeY2ogyl4aPluazMBtaf8OFMQCMS7-1juyPJUzxcBqpk5ikY1VpL2ybx3ghayI2mQsbpMuntCTmpFjru5rrfJa_1Uodq8yrKV9azbXKkFhn-l7t7XxM9cShERMojo0YBASSyIETSXALOnL2sk" data-is-external-image="true" ><figcaption>Brand Personality Workshop feature in No-Code tool, Notion</figcaption></figure>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/jHw2SKnhML0FEfNoKPN2o-YYaQBTpEZE-R5oevYNsuo9wWMzoHFAcNlRl8gWecejjQGqyKw9a7BH4-uGqEDJ8VcD0UrEJI3HtwpKtqlYjEkArDRskXMOPu4ZpRJcPIkOrhi0uCUr8dfVqqR-qZPAVL0" data-is-external-image="true" ><figcaption>Brand Personality Workshop feature in the Final App</figcaption></figure>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Product Think: Hacking No-Code/Low-Code Tools </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No-Code tools are a group of tools that allow you to build applications with a graphical interface (without code). Low-Code does the same but may enable you to insert code. For Typogram, we use no-code tools extensively in our product development process. Our no-code tech stack is Webflow, Notion, Figma, Make, and Airtable. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No-Code / Low-Code tools are excellent for building simplified features while conserving engineering resources. It allows you to build quickly and test for validation. <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1u3W91u40Obn-vgL33zilnV9LNZQWjLSCFx6nHgz9YXo/copy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">I created this kit</a> for brainstorming if there is a simplified version of a feature I can create with no code. Feel free to use this for your process (Click "Make a Copy" to duplicate my kit). </span></p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/typogram-no-code-worksheet-blog-3.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/typogram-no-code-worksheet-blog-3-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/typogram-no-code-worksheet-blog-3-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/typogram-no-code-worksheet-blog-3-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/typogram-no-code-worksheet-blog-3-lg.png 1024w"  alt="No-Code Product Development worksheet" width="1920" height="1080">
<figcaption >No-Code Brainstorming Kit</figcaption>
</figure>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">No-Code Tools We've Used for Typogram</span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Below are no-code tools we have used for Typogram I recommend with fantastic free tiers. I'm not affiliated with any of these tools. Learning difficulties are mainly determined by how long I spend learning the tools initially, how fast I can achieve results, and any prior knowledge needed.</span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Notion</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learning Difficulty: 3/5 </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Notion is a productivity and note-taking app capable of creating sharable webpages. You can also connect and embed other apps, like Google Drive, websites, and Figma.</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interaction capabilities: drag and drop, gallery view, table, sharable page</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use Case: Blog, Feature Creation, Knowledge Base, Issues Tracking</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typogram Use Case: core feature validation and mini-product, product management</span></li>
</ul>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Webflow </span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learning Difficulty: 5 /5</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Webflow is a low-code web builder. The editor is more intuitive if you know a bit about web programming (HTML, CSS, and even JavaScript). The style editor of Webflow allows you to create a landing page quickly. </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interaction capabilities: Website, CMS </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use Case: Websites </span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typogram Use Case: landing page and prototypes</span></li>
</ul>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/typogram-designSystem-webflow.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/typogram-designSystem-webflow-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/typogram-designSystem-webflow-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/typogram-designSystem-webflow-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/typogram-designSystem-webflow-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Typogram design system" width="1440" height="900">
<figcaption ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typogram’s design system page on Webflow</span></figcaption>
</figure>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make </span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learning Difficulty: 4 /5</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Make is a great automation tool with a generous free plan. Once you are used to the user interface, the editor is intuitive and allows you to create automation flows between different apps. I use Make to set up part of the payment system for Typogram. It saved us time from writing painful integrations and digging through APIs. However, tutorials can be challenging because of their recent name change from Integromat to Make. </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interaction capabilities: Connect and create automation from a variety of apps</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use Cases: Payment, leads tracking, content creation</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typogram Use Case: Payment &amp; License Code Delivery</span></li>
</ul>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Google Sheet</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learning Difficulty: 2 /5</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Excel on Google. Any Google suite product is very automation-friendly because most automation tools will offer Google products to connect in its free tier. You can also write simple code via Google App Script to interact with your data. There are also lots of tutorials available. </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Interaction capabilities: data creation / updating data</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Use Case: Data Storage, Delivery, User feedback tracking, leads tracking</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typogram Scenario: License redemption code storage and generation</span></li>
</ul>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strategy No.2:  Pre-Order with Landing Page </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After user testing and mini-product launches, we launched a pre-order for Typogram in March 2022. We offered a discounted lifetime deal for a single-brand license for this pre-order. Users can edit their logo forever inside our app as long as it's for the same brand. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At this point, we have yet to complete coding for the entire tool, like account management and payment. We wanted to gauge the interest first with our current set of features. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On the landing page, we had a demo video of our features, made using Webflow, which we still use for our product (if you go to our landing page now, you can still see the video). We also collected testimonials from our user testing sessions to feature on the landing page as social proofs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We launched this on Product Hunt and in the channels we've been developing (our newsletters) and got about 16 paid customers and 1,500 site visits in the first two weeks. Here is a </span><a href="https://typogram.co/blog/what-we-learned-from-launching-our-startup-on-product-hunt/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">detailed post</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> if you wish to see the stats from that launch. </span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/Q5UlwGCljMprpu1PBExVcI7tb7X5VQgE1ZuTSY2Vt1uiuzcMkEQWQO6GjMR9quexxwbqEg-wJTx9mJgN2yqKmZVKSxXHZ4AmlC_qmCrV5Fju0mMVLXUgxCNdStOtTfB29MaOqD2ZuUpi_u1XrO3nVQ4" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="our product hunt launch"><figcaption>Our product hunt launch for Typogram's pre-order</figcaption></figure>
<hr>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Short Term: Growth &amp; Traction </span></h2>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;">Find Your First 10 Customers and First 100 Registered Users </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Build it, and they will come, right? Unfortunately, no - : ( </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My hard lessons learned: you have to get tractions from "do things that don't scale." </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For Typogram, most of these come down to posting, sharing, and creating content around our product and topics potential users are excited about, followed by (mini) product/side project launches. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typogram was publicly launched in April 2023 and now has over 1,500 registered users. We have been successful with content marketing and Engineering as marketing for growth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Write content your potential new users will like. You can find topics for these by either interviewing them or searching on communities like Quora or Reddit. Then, find a platform where your users live and share your content consistently. </span></p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/FontDiscovery-research.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/FontDiscovery-research-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/FontDiscovery-research-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/FontDiscovery-research-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/FontDiscovery-research-lg.png 1024w"  alt="our research for our design content" width="1400" height="700">
<figcaption >Our research for our design content</figcaption>
</figure>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Newsletter </span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I wish someone told me sooner about newsletters - the great thing about them is that you can start one even if you don't have a product. I highly recommend this strategy because you are not tied to the platform, and you can start creating a community and finding supporters immediately.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Typogram has two weekly newsletters: a </span><a href="https://build.typogram.co/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">built-in public newsletter</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about our startup journey and </span><a href="https://fontdiscovery.typogram.co/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">a design newsletter</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, sharing beginner-friendly tips for typography, branding, and logo design. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In our newsletters, we share our startup journey. We also find topics to write about by researching what our users are interested in through Reddit. Initially, I was worried I couldn't maintain the consistency required for newsletters. Most days, it was easy to come up with topics to write about. Writing to an audience also helped me stay motivated. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Strategies for growing the newsletters include sharing on relevant communities, like Reddit, Indiehackers, and Twitter, and cross-promotion with other newsletters.</span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reddit</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reddit is an excellent place filled with communities of all sorts of interests. A proud Redditor since 2010s, Reddit is my preferred platform. Redditors hate spamming, and mods can permanently ban you from the site if you break the rules of their communities. In most subreddits, you will find rules on the right-hand side specifying community rules. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The most efficient way to market on Reddit is to ask for feedback about my project and focus on being helpful. Another useful technique is to filter posts by "Hot" and look at what topics people have written about that the followers of the subreddits already liked. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can then use these as prompts to create your content and posts. Lastly, you can be helpful in the comments and subtly plug your products. Comments are less moderated. </span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Power-up: F5Bot</span></h4>
<p><a href="https://f5bot.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">F5Bot</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> is a fantastic, free resource that helps you level up your Reddit game by allowing you to track keywords on those platforms. You will get posts with targeted keywords delivered to your inbox. I primarily use this tool to understand and engage with my potential users in the startup communities.</span></p>
<h4><span style="font-weight: 400;">Secret Hack</span></h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is possible to become a moderator of an abandoned subreddit. Many subreddits (anywhere from under 100 to over 10k in size) have inactive moderators. If you have enough karma points, you can apply to be a mod for inactive communities. Though you will have to perform extra labor of monitoring content, it could be very effective if it's in your niche.</span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Engineering as Marketing </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Engineering as Marketing can be more costly than other growth tactics in the short term, utilizing more time and effort in a concentrated block of time. However, if your engineering as marketing project takes off, you get a great new digital real estate, a nice traffic boost, and even SEO benefits. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, we launched </span><a href="https://codingfont.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coding Font</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as an Engineering as Marketing project for Typogram. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Because many potential users for Typogram are web devs and people who spent a lot of time in IDE, we wanted to create a fun little website where they could find their dream coding font. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we launched Coding Font on Product Hunt, we got </span><a href="https://build.typogram.co/p/stats-of-coding-font-launch"><span style="font-weight: 400;">​​22,000 visits on launch day</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Coding Font was featured on the front page of Hackernews and on blogs like BoingBoing and CSS Tricks, improving its backlink profile and site ranking. We seized this opportunity to add blog content and keywords to this site. As a result, we got newsletter sign-ups, sales, and continuous referral traffic. </span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4HCXr-QG3213ko9g6RkGap8KZiuSWeAmolfxeDYRjEXnk4iFzvyW1GlKM8FmodSo4-LwbQvcmHJEJVqjfBaQ5LC2pugQNTAGE8sXrVHqJgRgx2o24GtlcYepXI6eC7Fk2OuIFQZuNCz6lpvL-AfATu4" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Our most successful engineering as marketing game, Coding Font"><figcaption>Our most successful engineering as marketing game, Coding Font</figcaption></figure>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Long-Term Growth: </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">SEO/Organic Traffic via Long-Tail Keywords </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">SEO gets a bad rep from email spam by link-building agencies, but it's one of the best ways to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">gain free traffic and attract potential users to your site. The most important thing about SEO: it takes time to develop and grow. Once we validated ideas for Typogram, we started paying closer attention to SEO and how we can leverage SEO to increase organic traffic. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can target long tail keywords, which are three to five words long search queries. Long tails are usually more niche, less search volume, and less competitive. For example, we have the </span><a href="https://typogram.co/font-discovery"><span style="font-weight: 400;">FontDiscovery(our design newsletter) archive</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for Typogram for our long tail search queries. These posts give us a nice traffic boost, over 1k per month. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I highly recommend Ahrefs' YouTube lessons. Please force yourself to watch them. You won't regret it, and you might even like it.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/Font-Discovery-Blog.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/Font-Discovery-Blog-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/Font-Discovery-Blog-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/Font-Discovery-Blog-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/53/responsive/Font-Discovery-Blog-lg.png 1024w"  alt="FontDiscovery archive " width="1600" height="1060">
<figcaption >FontDiscovery archive </figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/0oEpakJ6_ybu613hMTE9vv9Q7Ul38vt8Zxi_3G4C6ImgzWDxWvO9uGMKNmRpumCRNnXfHHJoBQDAKViQRZtXVum9eotgwRLUAyLGV2mEuDqWFejS3o_0xSld9h5Cv3zWtuv_rGM9dFrF_mHUlyi_O4A" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Some promising results from long tail keywords"><figcaption>Promising results from long tail keywords</figcaption></figure>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Last Words </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">My last words are about ads. I researched about ads but haven’t spent money on any. Based on my learnings, I don’t think my budget will yield meaningful results. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another thing I didn’t get a chance to talk about in this post is one-time launch channels, like Product Hunt and IndieHackers. We are also experimenting with launching in LTD (Lifetime Deals) Facebook groups soon.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I plan to update this post with these launch channels once we launch in the LTD Facebook groups.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you liked this post, I would appreciate it if you could share it with someone who might find it useful. You can also follow me on </span><a href="https://twitter.com/HuaTweets"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Twitter</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, subscribe to our </span><a href="https://build.typogram.co/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">build-in-public newsletter</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, or check out what we are building at Typogram.</span></p>
<p><br><br></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Product Update No.13 : Modularizing Brand Personality</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://typogram.co/blog/product-update-no13-modularizing-brand-personality/"/>
        <id>https://typogram.co/blog/product-update-no13-modularizing-brand-personality/</id>
            <category term="Inside Typogram"/>

        <updated>2023-09-07T22:30:40-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/52/typogramProductUpdate13-a.png" alt="Product Update No.13 : Modularizing Brand Personality" />
                    How is Typogram development going? Since our last update, we have been&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/52/typogramProductUpdate13-a.png" alt="Product Update No.13 : Modularizing Brand Personality" />
                <blockquote>
<p><strong>How is Typogram development going?</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Since our last update, we have been busy implementing features and changes per your feedback and suggestions. Here is what we've working on this month!</p>
<h2 class="header-with-anchor-widget"><strong>Modularizing Brand Personality</strong></h2>
<p>During our <a href="https://typogram.co/blog/typogram-product-updates-no12-in-app-tutorial-videos-streamlined-brand-name-change-modularized-app-components/" title="typogram product update">last product update</a>, we shared about our new product thinking: modular steps and shareable work-in-progress. We are making Typogram more modular, making workflow between steps more flexible, and design work more shareable. </p>
<p>In the last few weeks, we have been working on modularizing the Brand Personality Step. I’ve been (Wenting) making two big changes to Typogram, starting with the brand personality step. </p>
<h3 class="header-with-anchor-widget"><strong>Changing the Base</strong></h3>
<p>I initially built Typogram using a javascript framework called Vue. To improve the user experience, I changed the base of Typogram to Svelte. Svelte pre-renders our app and eliminates the need for loading additional JavaScript files, which our previous framework, Vue, lacked. This change will help our app run faster, improving the overall experience!</p>
<h3 class="header-with-anchor-widget"><strong>Making Parts &amp; Adding Share</strong></h3>
<p>I’ve also been “modularizing” our app, splitting the app into smaller parts. Modularizing Typogram allows the potential for less linear workflows for users (a popular request ), makes things neater and easier to manage, and makes it possible to reuse the parts to create mini standalone apps for steps like Brand Personality. </p>
<p>Here is a sneak peek of what I’ve added to the Brand Personality step – sharable social (Instagram) post that you can create and customize to share and test drive your designs immediately with your audience.</p>
<div class="captioned-image-container">
<figure>
<div class="image2-inset"><picture><source type="image/webp" srcset="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_424,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F1a874421-2a25-44ad-aef5-0cd6431a6df8_538x593.gif 424w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_848,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F1a874421-2a25-44ad-aef5-0cd6431a6df8_538x593.gif 848w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1272,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F1a874421-2a25-44ad-aef5-0cd6431a6df8_538x593.gif 1272w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F1a874421-2a25-44ad-aef5-0cd6431a6df8_538x593.gif 1456w" sizes="100vw"></picture>
<figure class="sizing-normal" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  title="image: The sharable graphics can be customized with different color themes" src="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F1a874421-2a25-44ad-aef5-0cd6431a6df8_538x593.gif" data-is-external-image="true"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_424,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F1a874421-2a25-44ad-aef5-0cd6431a6df8_538x593.gif 424w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_848,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F1a874421-2a25-44ad-aef5-0cd6431a6df8_538x593.gif 848w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1272,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F1a874421-2a25-44ad-aef5-0cd6431a6df8_538x593.gif 1272w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F1a874421-2a25-44ad-aef5-0cd6431a6df8_538x593.gif 1456w" alt="image: The sharable graphics can be customized with different color themes" width="930" height="1037" loading="lazy" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://substack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/1a874421-2a25-44ad-aef5-0cd6431a6df8_538x593.gif&quot;,&quot;srcNoWatermark&quot;:null,&quot;fullscreen&quot;:null,&quot;imageSize&quot;:null,&quot;height&quot;:593,&quot;width&quot;:538,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:null,&quot;alt&quot;:&quot;image: The sharable graphics can be customized with different color themes&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:null,&quot;href&quot;:null,&quot;belowTheFold&quot;:true,&quot;topImage&quot;:false,&quot;internalRedirect&quot;:null}"></figure>
<figcaption >image: The sharable graphics can be customized with different color themes</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</figure>
</div>
<p>You can customize the colors of the post as well as the styles. I’m still playing around with more unique customization options: for example, this “brand reveal effect” that allows you to control the shading of letters in your post. Here is a sneak peek of the work in progress. Let me know what you think!</p>
<div class="captioned-image-container">
<figure>
<div class="image2-inset"><picture><source type="image/webp" srcset="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_424,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F6a0dd3f2-865c-4223-98e3-8fed49e568a2_1076x1184.gif 424w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_848,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F6a0dd3f2-865c-4223-98e3-8fed49e568a2_1076x1184.gif 848w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1272,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F6a0dd3f2-865c-4223-98e3-8fed49e568a2_1076x1184.gif 1272w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F6a0dd3f2-865c-4223-98e3-8fed49e568a2_1076x1184.gif 1456w" sizes="100vw"></picture>
<figure class="sizing-normal" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  title="image: Experimental interactive “fun-piece” — The Brand Reveal" src="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F6a0dd3f2-865c-4223-98e3-8fed49e568a2_1076x1184.gif" data-is-external-image="true"  sizes="100vw" srcset="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_424,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F6a0dd3f2-865c-4223-98e3-8fed49e568a2_1076x1184.gif 424w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_848,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F6a0dd3f2-865c-4223-98e3-8fed49e568a2_1076x1184.gif 848w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1272,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F6a0dd3f2-865c-4223-98e3-8fed49e568a2_1076x1184.gif 1272w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_lossy/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F6a0dd3f2-865c-4223-98e3-8fed49e568a2_1076x1184.gif 1456w" alt="image: Experimental interactive “fun-piece” — The Brand Reveal" width="1076" height="1184" loading="lazy" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://substack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/6a0dd3f2-865c-4223-98e3-8fed49e568a2_1076x1184.gif&quot;,&quot;srcNoWatermark&quot;:null,&quot;fullscreen&quot;:null,&quot;imageSize&quot;:null,&quot;height&quot;:1184,&quot;width&quot;:1076,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:null,&quot;alt&quot;:&quot;image: Experimental interactive “fun-piece” — The Brand Reveal&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:null,&quot;href&quot;:null,&quot;belowTheFold&quot;:true,&quot;topImage&quot;:false,&quot;internalRedirect&quot;:null}"></figure>
<figcaption >image: Experimental interactive “fun-piece” — The Brand Reveal</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Once this step is completed, it can function as a standalone app or be part of your full Typogram experience. You can share your work with your audience or save it as part of your inspiration library to help you design and create. We will share more soon. Let us know you think!</p>
<h3 class="header-with-anchor-widget"><strong>Hearing From You</strong></h3>
<p>We’d love to hear more of your thoughts if you have already tried the software. Please share them with us by directly replying to this email or filling out this <a href="https://typogram.us21.list-manage.com/track/click?u=524fd774e21060e9ef6f46b01&amp;id=5a1cc60557&amp;e=9d422adcad" rel="">very short feedback form</a>. If you haven’t tried, we encourage you to create an account and use the Free Trial to play with the tool.</p>
<p>If you encounter any issues, please help us improve by reporting the issue from inside the app or directly through <a href="https://typogram.us21.list-manage.com/track/click?u=524fd774e21060e9ef6f46b01&amp;id=cf27a97c40&amp;e=9d422adcad" rel="">here</a>. You can also chat with us via the chat window inside the app. We are online during the daytime in the EST time zone (and some night time too).</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Build Your Brand With Our Brand Personality Workshop Kit</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://typogram.co/blog/building-your-brand-with-our-brand-personality-workshop-kit/"/>
        <id>https://typogram.co/blog/building-your-brand-with-our-brand-personality-workshop-kit/</id>
            <category term="Branding"/>

        <updated>2023-09-07T00:25:38-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/NewsletterCover-96-3.png" alt="Typogram&#x27;s Brand Personality Workshop Kit" />
                    Not sure how to create logo, brand design, or brand kit for&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/NewsletterCover-96-3.png" alt="Typogram&#x27;s Brand Personality Workshop Kit" />
                <blockquote>
<p>Not sure how to create logo, brand design, or brand kit for your new business? Don’t know how to start with fonts, color, and typography systems for your brand? Do not worry. We got you back! </p>
</blockquote>
<p>Today we introduce one of our favorite tools we’ve created: <a href="https://workshop.typogram.co/" title="Typogram’s Brand Personality Workshop Kit">Typogram’s Brand Personality Workshop Kit</a>. Our branding workshop kit is made for folks with little to no marketing and branding design experience and is a fun activity that will help you start thinking creatively about your company. By following the three-step exercise in our free workshop kit, you will walk away with brand personalities and visual directions for your company, giving you ideas to build your brand designs: logos, fonts, colors, and typography systems.</p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is brand personality? </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inside Typogram, the first thing you complete is figuring out your brand personality. A brand is a person’s feeling about a product, a service, or a company. A brand personality is a “personality” or human characteristics we can assign to a brand. You can influence how people feel about your brand by creating a brand personality and then communicating the brand personality visually through the brand’s design directions, like fonts, logos, typography, colors, and imagery.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It can be overwhelming to start figuring out your brand personality, especially if you have no marketing background or have never thought about branding that way. Therefore, we created a fun, interactive workshop kit to help you identify your brand personality. </span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/brandPersonality.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/responsive/brandPersonality-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/responsive/brandPersonality-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/responsive/brandPersonality-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/responsive/brandPersonality-lg.png 1024w"  alt="what is a brand " width="1600" height="900"></figure>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">What is inside our Brand Personality Workshop Kit?  </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This kit contains: </span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Explanation worksheets with interactive exercises help you understand and identify brand personality</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Custom brand personality cards with visual examples </span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By completing the three-step exercise in our workshop kit, you will learn, eliminate and finalize a chosen five top brand personalities, serving as visual directions and inspirations for your brand. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This workshop kit can accommodate a solopreneur or a small team of founders. It can be completed as a self-paced workshop or a collaborative team exercise. The exercise takes anywhere from 30 minutes to one hour, depending on the number of participants. We highly recommend you try this with your teammate or co-founder – it is a great team alignment exercise to start conversations about the visions for your business. As for file formats, the workshop is available in Google Slides, Notion, and PDF, so you may elect to complete this digitally or print it out on paper to get more hands-on. </span></p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/brandPersonalityWorkshopPDF.gif" alt="our brand personality workshop kit in PDF format  " width="1200" height="900">
<figcaption >our brand personality workshop kit in PDF format  </figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/slider-digital-pic1-2x.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/responsive/slider-digital-pic1-2x-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/responsive/slider-digital-pic1-2x-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/responsive/slider-digital-pic1-2x-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/50/responsive/slider-digital-pic1-2x-lg.png 1024w"  alt="our brand personality workshop kit inside Google slides" width="1440" height="1500">
<figcaption >our brand personality workshop kit inside Google slides</figcaption>
</figure>
<hr>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">How did we develop this kit? </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our brand personality workshop kit originated and evolved from Typogram’s product development process. Initially, we wanted to identify a user experience flow for the brand personality feature inside the Typogram app: how can we make the brand personality a valuable feature to the users? What specific interactions can we include at this step, and what do they look like? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With many hypotheses, we focused on shipping quickly for testing. We created this workshop using three popular No-Code tools easily accessible to our potential users: PDF, Google Slides, and Notion. Now that we have sped up the product development process using No-Code, we can focus on testing and making the UX as rewarding as possible. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The end product featured a main flow: users sort through different cards of brand personality and each time, they sort and choose using various methods: First, they identify based on a list of words and then narrow down based on images. Ultimately, users land on five words as visual themes/directions for their logos. Observing from our user testing session that branding is a starting point for conversation - we designed the workshop to work for solopreneurs or a team. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We organized user testing sessions and received great feedback. The success of user testing validated the flow and design of our brand personality feature inside Typogram! Because of the overwhelmingly positive response, we now make this kit a free resource for our community. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Access our Brand Personality Workshop Kit</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can download our free </span><a href="https://workshop.typogram.co/" title="Typogram's Brand Personality Workshop Kit"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Brand Personality Workshop Kit</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on our website. It is available in PDF and Google Slide formats.</span><br><br><br><br><br><br><br></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Typogram Product Updates: In-App Tutorial Videos &amp; Modularized App Components</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://typogram.co/blog/typogram-product-updates-no12-in-app-tutorial-videos-streamlined-brand-name-change-modularized-app-components/"/>
        <id>https://typogram.co/blog/typogram-product-updates-no12-in-app-tutorial-videos-streamlined-brand-name-change-modularized-app-components/</id>
            <category term="Inside Typogram"/>

        <updated>2023-08-05T15:55:29-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/49/ProductUpdateNo12.png" alt="Typogram Product Update: In-App Tutorial Videos &amp; Modularized App Components" />
                    How is Typogram development going? Since our last update, we have been&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/49/ProductUpdateNo12.png" alt="Typogram Product Update: In-App Tutorial Videos &amp; Modularized App Components" />
                <blockquote>
<p><strong style="font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit;">How is Typogram development going?</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Since our last update, we have been busy working per your feedback and suggestions. Here is what we worked on. </p>
<h1> </h1>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">In-App Tutorial Videos </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A popular request we received is adding tutorial videos, and we hear you! We have added short in-app tutorial videos that help you along the way in Brand Personality, Brand Color, Distinctive Logo (Logo Editor), and Kerning steps. Each video showcases the available features in that particular step. The short videos present you with how-tos, instructions, and tooltips so that you can find our helpful features. You can find the videos embedded in the learning material posts. We hope you find them useful, and please let us know if you have any feedback.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/49/logoEditorVideoScreenshotUpdate.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/49/responsive/logoEditorVideoScreenshotUpdate-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/49/responsive/logoEditorVideoScreenshotUpdate-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/49/responsive/logoEditorVideoScreenshotUpdate-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/49/responsive/logoEditorVideoScreenshotUpdate-lg.png 1024w"  alt="img: in-app video inside learning material" width="786" height="536">
<figcaption ><span style="font-weight: 400;">img: in-app video inside learning material</span></figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/49/logoEditorVideoUpdate-optimize.gif" alt="img: in-app video showing tips on product features" width="909" height="703">
<figcaption ><span style="font-weight: 400;">img: in-app video showing tips on product features</span></figcaption>
</figure>
<h1> </h1>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Streamlined Brand Name Change </span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Another popular request we receive is brand name change. Because Typogram offers a one-brand lifetime license, you are locked down to a brand name once you purchase a paid license. However, we understand that sometimes, accidents happen. There can be spelling errors or incorrect name entries.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The old process for the brand name change was manually sending us an email or via the chat widget. Starting today, we have a better, more streamlined process: you can initiate a name change directly in the app through your project dashboard. Under the appropriate project, click “Request Change Brand Name,” to enter a new name for approval. It’ll usually approve within 24 hours.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/49/brandNameChangeEditUpdate_2-2.gif" alt="img: request to change brand name" width="1440" height="900">
<figcaption ><span style="font-weight: 400;">img: Request to change brand name</span></figcaption>
</figure>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Upcoming: Modularized App Components &amp; Expanding Brand Personality Workshop</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are currently reworking our app from the ground up with a brand-new direction to product thinking: </span><strong>modular steps and shareable work-in-progress.</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> We take pride in our unique eight-step process for creating a professional brand, but its implementation in the app seems rigid regarding workflow adherence. You must go through a series of steps to reach the final destination—Brand Guidelines—which is the only place and time where you can share your work.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The new Typogram maintains the same brand design philosophies and workflows but is much more modular and flexible. We broke ground on this new app direction with Typogram’s first step—Brand Personality. Once completed, it will function as a modular component that can either stand alone as a mini app or serve as a segue to the full Typogram experience. The Brand Personality app will also feature a more visually stunning presentation you can save and publish. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our plans for the future: every single step is a standalone app, much more robust, but at the same time, it is still part of the full Typogram experience. The brand design journey can start anywhere and in any order. The work product of each step is presented in a much more visually-impressive way, and you can save and share with your team or community to get feedback.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let us know what you think of this future direction!</span></p>
<h1> </h1>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hearing from You</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’d love to hear more of your thoughts if you have already tried the software. Please share them with us by directly replying to this email or filling out this </span><a href="https://tally.so/r/mVGEQv"><span style="font-weight: 400;">very short feedback form</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If you haven’t tried, we encourage you to create an account and use the Free Trial to play with the tool.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you encounter any issues, please help us improve by reporting the issue from inside the app or directly through </span><a href="https://tally.so/r/mOQxJ7"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You can also chat with us via the chat window inside the app. We are online during the daytime in the EST time zone (and some night time too).</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Typogram Product Updates: Brand Guideline PDF Export </title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://typogram.co/blog/typogram-product-update-no11-brand-guideline-pdf-export/"/>
        <id>https://typogram.co/blog/typogram-product-update-no11-brand-guideline-pdf-export/</id>
            <category term="Startups"/>
            <category term="Inside Typogram"/>

        <updated>2023-07-31T23:42:49-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/46/typogramUpdateNo11.png" alt="" />
                    How is Typogram development going? Since our last update, we have been&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/46/typogramUpdateNo11.png" alt="" />
                <blockquote>
<p><strong>How is Typogram development going?</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Since our last update, we have been busy implementing features and changes per your feedback and suggestions. Here are the new features we have in the pipeline! </p>
<hr>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Export Brand Guidelines PDF </span></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Brand Guidelines PDF feature is now available inside the app! You can create a unique guidelines page for your brand and generate a printer-friendly pdf copy to either print it out for yourself as a reminder of the key assets of your brand or share the PDF with a designer you are working with. You can find the Print PDF option on the left sidebar and top right navigation on your published brand guidelines page.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/46/Print-Guidelines-as-PDF_lrg.gif" alt="brand guidelines pdf" width="1440" height="900">
<figcaption ><span style="font-weight: 400;">brand guidelines pdf</span></figcaption>
</figure>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Multi-Select Design Elements </span></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sometimes, you may want to implement the same design action on multiple parts of a logo – for example, making a group of letters into a smaller font size or different font. Being able to select multiple objects makes this action easier.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now inside the logo editor, in addition to single-select, you can select multiple element by using the SHIFT key. Simply select the design element, press SHIFT, and make another selection to enable multi-select.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/46/multi-select.gif" alt="multiple selections" width="1440" height="900">
<figcaption ><span style="font-weight: 400;">multiple selections</span></figcaption>
</figure>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">An Update on Undo/Redo </span></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We have been working on Undo/Redo and this feature is now ready and shipped in the app. You can find Undo/Redo in the logo editor. Click on the right or left arrow to go back and forth between steps. We added an additional touch: hover over the clock icon and click on the numbers to return to a specific step in your design journey.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/46/Undo-Redo.gif" alt="Undo/Redo in action inside the logo editor" width="1440" height="900">
<figcaption ><span style="font-weight: 400;">Undo/Redo in action inside the logo editor</span></figcaption>
</figure>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hearing from You</span></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We’d love to hear more of your thoughts if you have already tried the software. Please share them with us by directly replying to this email or filling out this </span><a href="https://tally.so/r/mVGEQv"><span style="font-weight: 400;">very short feedback form</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. If you haven’t tried, we encourage you to create an account and use the Free Trial to play with the tool.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you encounter any issues, please help us improve by reporting the issue from inside the app or directly through </span><a href="https://tally.so/r/mOQxJ7"><span style="font-weight: 400;">here</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. You can also chat with us via the chat window inside the app. We are online during the daytime in the EST time zone (and some night time too).</span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Celebrating Pride Month: Colors of Rainbow in Branding</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://typogram.co/blog/celebrating-pride-month-colors-of-rainbow-in-branding/"/>
        <id>https://typogram.co/blog/celebrating-pride-month-colors-of-rainbow-in-branding/</id>
            <category term="Branding"/>

        <updated>2023-07-24T18:42:52-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/prideCover-8.png" alt="" />
                    It’s Pride Month! The rainbow colors are the symbol of the LGBTQ+&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/prideCover-8.png" alt="" />
                <div class="captioned-image-container">
<figure>
<div class="image2-inset">
<div class="image-link-expand">It’s Pride Month! The rainbow colors are the symbol of the LGBTQ+ community. It’s pretty cool how the rainbow has come to represent and unite people of diverse backgrounds and identities. In this post, we look at what each color means for branding. </div>
</div>
</figure>
</div>
<h2 class="header-with-anchor-widget">Red</h2>
<p>Red often associates with words like energetic, liveliness, boldness, adventurous, excitement, or speed. It attracts attention more than any other.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Coca-Cola: The iconic beverage company has a red logo and packaging, with the red color symbolizing excitement, energy, and refreshment.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Target: The retail giant’s logo features a red bullseye.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Netflix: The streaming service’s red “N” logo.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Pinterest: The social media platform’s logo consists of a red “P.”</p>
<div class="captioned-image-container">
<figure>
<div class="image2-inset">
<figure class="post__image" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/1-cocacola_red.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/1-cocacola_red-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/1-cocacola_red-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/1-cocacola_red-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/1-cocacola_red-lg.png 1024w"  alt="cocacola-red" width="1456" height="761"></figure>
<figcaption >Coca-Cola Logo</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</figure>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="header-with-anchor-widget">Orange</h2>
<p>Orange is often associated with words like energetic, comfort, creativity, accessibility, and youthful. It offers positivism, sitting between the cheerfulness of yellow and the boldness of red.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Nickelodeon: The children’s television network uses a bright orange color in its logo and branding, resonating with the playful and energetic nature of the channel.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Home Depot: The home improvement retailer.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>SoundCloud: The music-sharing platform features an orange cloud logo.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Fanta: The soda brand has an orange logo and packaging.</p>
<div class="captioned-image-container">
<figure>
<figcaption class="image-caption">
<figure class="post__image" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/3-Nickelodeon_orange.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/3-Nickelodeon_orange-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/3-Nickelodeon_orange-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/3-Nickelodeon_orange-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/3-Nickelodeon_orange-lg.png 1024w"  alt="nickelodeon-orange" width="1456" height="761"></figure>
<figcaption >Nickelodeon Logo</figcaption>
</figure>
</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 class="header-with-anchor-widget">Yellow</h2>
<p>Yellow is often associated with words like happiness, lively, friendly, playful, and warmth. It creates an atmosphere of curiosity and optimism.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>McDonald’s: The iconic fast-food restaurant chain has a yellow “M” logo, known as the “Golden Arches.” The yellow color evokes feelings of happiness, aligning with the brand’s family-friendly image.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Best Buy: The electronics retailer has a yellow price tag logo. </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Nikon: The camera and imaging brand uses a yellow font for its logo. </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>IKEA: The Swedish furniture and home goods retailer has a blue and yellow logo.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<figure class="post__image" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/4-mcdonald_yellow.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/4-mcdonald_yellow-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/4-mcdonald_yellow-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/4-mcdonald_yellow-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/4-mcdonald_yellow-lg.png 1024w"  alt="mcdonald-yellow" width="1456" height="761"></figure>
<figcaption >McDonald’s Logo</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2 class="header-with-anchor-widget">Green</h2>
<p>Green is often associated with growth, freshness, health, and relaxation. It creates a sense of calm as it is abundant in nature.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Starbucks: The global coffeehouse chain has a green logo featuring a siren. The green color evokes feelings of relaxation and environmental consciousness, reflecting the brand’s focus on sustainability.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Spotify: The music streaming service. </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Android: The operating system by Google has a green logo in the shape of a robot. </p>
</li>
</ol>
<figure class="post__image" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/5-starbucks_green-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/5-starbucks_green-2-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/5-starbucks_green-2-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/5-starbucks_green-2-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/5-starbucks_green-2-lg.png 1024w"  alt="" width="1456" height="761"></figure>
<figcaption >Starbucks Logo</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2 class="header-with-anchor-widget">Blue</h2>
<p>Blue is associated with security, trustworthiness, wisdom, and peacefulness. It generates a sense of security and reliability and is an appetite suppressant.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Facebook: The social media platform. The choice of blue conveys a sense of trust, reliability, and communication, aligning with the brand’s mission to connect people.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>IBM: The technology and consulting corporation. </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Ford: The automotive manufacturer. </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Visa: The financial services company. </p>
</li>
</ol>
<figure class="post__image" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/2-facebook_blue-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/2-facebook_blue-2-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/2-facebook_blue-2-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/2-facebook_blue-2-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/2-facebook_blue-2-lg.png 1024w"  alt="facebook-blue" width="1456" height="761"></figure>
<figcaption >Facebook Logo</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2 class="header-with-anchor-widget">Indigo</h2>
<p>Indigo is commonly associated with creativity, innovation, and intuition. It creates a sense of depth, sophistication, and mystery.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Yahoo!: The web service provider. The color choice reflects the brand's approach to innovation and creativity in the digital space.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Monster.com: The employment website.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Cadbury: The chocolate and confectionery brand.</p>
<div class="captioned-image-container"> </div>
</li>
</ol>
<figure class="post__image" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/6-yahoo_purple.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/6-yahoo_purple-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/6-yahoo_purple-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/6-yahoo_purple-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/6-yahoo_purple-lg.png 1024w"  alt="yahoo-logo" width="1456" height="761"></figure>
<figcaption >Yahoo  Logo</figcaption>
</figure>
<h2 class="header-with-anchor-widget">Violet</h2>
<p>Violet is often associated with mystics and adventures. It generates excitement while striking a balance.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Twitch: The live streaming platform. The color choice conveys a sense of creativity, innovation, and immersion, aligning with the brand’s focus on interactive entertainment and community building.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Hallmark: The greeting card and gift company.  </p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Avid: The media technology company. </p>
</li>
</ol>
<div class="captioned-image-container">
<figure>
<div>
<figure class="post__image" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/7-twitch_purlpe.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/7-twitch_purlpe-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/7-twitch_purlpe-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/7-twitch_purlpe-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/responsive/7-twitch_purlpe-lg.png 1024w"  alt="twitch-purple" width="1456" height="761"></figure>
<figcaption >Twitch Logo</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<figcaption class="image-caption"></figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<div><hr></div>
<p>In honor of Pride Month, we have explored the fascinating world of color psychology and the significance of each color in the rainbow, and its meaning to branding. It is evident that each hue, including those beyond the colors we covered today, carries a unique message, tone, and emotion. Typogram offers an interactive experience for you to delve deeper into the brand psychology behind each hue value from 0° to 360°! </p>
<p>As you continue to encounter these colors in branding, remember their deeper meanings and the sense of inclusion they represent. Happy Pride Month!</p>
<div class="captioned-image-container">
<figure>
<div class="image2-inset post__image--wide"><figure class="post__image"><source type="image/webp" srcset="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_424,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9dd91923-0529-4455-a231-c61160cdb12e_882x562.gif 424w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_848,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9dd91923-0529-4455-a231-c61160cdb12e_882x562.gif 848w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1272,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9dd91923-0529-4455-a231-c61160cdb12e_882x562.gif 1272w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_webp,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9dd91923-0529-4455-a231-c61160cdb12e_882x562.gif 1456w" sizes="100vw"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/45/9dd91923-0529-4455-a231-c61160cdb12e_882x562.gif" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_424,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9dd91923-0529-4455-a231-c61160cdb12e_882x562.gif 424w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_848,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9dd91923-0529-4455-a231-c61160cdb12e_882x562.gif 848w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1272,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9dd91923-0529-4455-a231-c61160cdb12e_882x562.gif 1272w, https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F9dd91923-0529-4455-a231-c61160cdb12e_882x562.gif 1456w" alt="view color tips" width="882" height="562" loading="lazy" data-attrs="{&quot;src&quot;:&quot;https://substack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/9dd91923-0529-4455-a231-c61160cdb12e_882x562.gif&quot;,&quot;fullscreen&quot;:null,&quot;imageSize&quot;:null,&quot;height&quot;:562,&quot;width&quot;:882,&quot;resizeWidth&quot;:null,&quot;bytes&quot;:739171,&quot;alt&quot;:null,&quot;title&quot;:null,&quot;type&quot;:&quot;image/gif&quot;,&quot;href&quot;:null,&quot;belowTheFold&quot;:true,&quot;topImage&quot;:false,&quot;internalRedirect&quot;:null}"></figure></picture></div>
<figcaption class="image-caption">View Color Tips</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p> </p>
<div class="subscription-widget-wrap">
<div class="subscription-widget show-subscribe">
<div class="preamble"> </div>
</div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Learnings From Our Second Product Hunt Launch</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://typogram.co/blog/learnings-from-our-second-product-hunt-launch/"/>
        <id>https://typogram.co/blog/learnings-from-our-second-product-hunt-launch/</id>
            <category term="Startups"/>
            <category term="Inside Typogram"/>

        <updated>2023-07-24T18:40:32-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/productHuntLaunchUpdate.png" alt="Learnings From Our Second Product Hunt Launch" />
                    Our launch had high aspirations to aim for the top #1 Product&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/productHuntLaunchUpdate.png" alt="Learnings From Our Second Product Hunt Launch" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our launch had high aspirations to aim for the top #1 Product of the Day position, but unfortunately, it didn’t pan out as expected in the beginning. There were a variety of reasons for this, which I will expand on later. Despite this setback, we still launched our product with the support of our community and gained new users, both free and paid! We’re still proud of what we accomplished and are grateful for the support we received.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br></span></p>
<h2>We fell through a crack on Product Hunt</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Product Hunt, the popular platform for discovering new and innovative products, has its fair share of quirks. One such quirk is the potential to fall through the cracks and not get featured on the front page.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What products get featured on the front page and why? From Product Hunt’s response to our complaint, it seems that manual curation plays a substantial role in their selection process:</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I very much regret the experience. We try our best to feature everything that is eligible and that we think will be a value add to our community. Every now and then, unfortunately, we do miss a great launch. — Product Hunt Support</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">I think that the Product Hunt team must employ a combination of strategies to manage this workload efficiently. It seems implausible for a manual process alone to handle such a volume, making me question how they strike the right balance between human curation and algorithmic assistance. Whatever they do, mistakes happen, which is unfortunately on our part.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The “falling into Product Hunt crack” actually happens much more often than I realized. Just today, I observed another company that suffered the same fate as Typogram last Tuesday.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Look at the diagram from </span><a href="https://hunted.space/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="font-weight: 400;">hunted.space</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, a site that collects Product Hunt launch statistics and analyzes trends. On the launch day of Typogram, for the first four hours, Hunted Space couldn’t find Typogram and therefore didn’t crawl any stats, reporting a flat line for 0 votes until it jumped to 40 votes suddenly:</span></p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/eb51025a-c194-48ab-8e37-b15761b9e762_980x385.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/eb51025a-c194-48ab-8e37-b15761b9e762_980x385-xs.jpg 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/eb51025a-c194-48ab-8e37-b15761b9e762_980x385-sm.jpg 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/eb51025a-c194-48ab-8e37-b15761b9e762_980x385-md.jpg 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/eb51025a-c194-48ab-8e37-b15761b9e762_980x385-lg.jpg 1024w"  alt="Comparing Typogram to the product that secured the 2nd position. Typogram has a flat line in the beginning section" width="980" height="385">
<figcaption >Comparing Typogram to the product that secured the 2nd position. Typogram has a flat line in the beginning section</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, similar to Typogram’s fate, there is another product called TeamGPT that get buried for a couple of hours before they see the light of day:</span></p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/526644a2-2dea-477d-b683-897a5274311b_980x385.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/526644a2-2dea-477d-b683-897a5274311b_980x385-xs.jpg 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/526644a2-2dea-477d-b683-897a5274311b_980x385-sm.jpg 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/526644a2-2dea-477d-b683-897a5274311b_980x385-md.jpg 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/526644a2-2dea-477d-b683-897a5274311b_980x385-lg.jpg 1024w"  alt="TeamGPT got buried for about two hours. It also has a flat line in the beginning section." width="980" height="385">
<figcaption ><span style="font-weight: 400;">TeamGPT got buried for about two hours. It also has a flat line in the beginning section.</span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The flat line in the beginning doesn’t mean the product didn’t get votes during those times. It just means that they got no exposure that the stats crawler didn’t crawl. </span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During this time, Typogram is live on Product Hunt, but people only find it through the link we shared. In other words, we are sending traffic to Product Hunt, not the other way around. The moment we get unburied at hour 4, we already got 40 votes, purely from our own people! That is a miracle in itself! </span></p>
<h2>How Launching on Product Hunt Works</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We ask our community to visit Product Hunt and upvote our product, which in turn boosts our ranking. As our position improves, we attract more traffic from Product Hunt’s user base. Ideally, a successful launch results in significantly more traffic flowing from Product Hunt to our product than what we initially directed toward them. Unfortunately, it may not be the case for our launch this time.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When we finally got unburied, we had 40 votes and ranked #13. Ranking in #13 means we only get the exposure and traffic that belongs to #13, which is less than #12, which is less than #11 … you get my point. Assuming all products are equally interesting and have the same upvote ratio (the number of votes divided by the number of visitors), our vote gap is only getting larger and larger by default.</span></p>
<p><strong>In order to climb up, we need to:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>be more interesting so that the upvote ratio is higher</strong></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><strong>lead more outside traffic to your Product Hunt post</strong></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The #1 is done prior; nothing we can change on the launch day. I think our product is very unique and interesting. We trend up really quickly after we get onto the front page, thanks to that.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The #2 is counter-intuitive. We launch on Product Hunt to get more people to visit us, not the other way around. But in order to get more exposure, we have to send more traffic first. We continue to ask our community to show up and support us, and you all did. We climbed all the way from #13 to #5 in the early afternoon!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Each position on Product Hunt corresponds to a certain level of traffic. To optimize your launch, it’s crucial to secure a top position as early as possible.</span></p>
<p><strong>The traffic generated during a launch is determined by two factors:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong> Your position on Product Hunt</strong></li>
<li><strong> The duration you maintain that position</strong></li>
</ol>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Even if some product manages to climb from the bottom to the top #1 spot at the last minute and earn the “Product of the Day” title, it won’t make a significant impact, as it would only benefit from one minute of the top position’s traffic. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We enjoyed about half a day of position #5’s traffic, and the other half day we get very little traffic.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The launch experience serves as a reminder of the importance of building our own audience. While leveraging platforms like Product Hunt can be beneficial, their outcomes are not always reliable. I was confident that our launch would secure the top #1 or #2 spot, especially since I had previously achieved #2 with a hobby project, Symbols to Copy. In comparison, Typogram is a much more interesting and robust product. Nonetheless, this experience underscores the need to focus on cultivating a community of user base independently.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Our community carried us through the launch. Without their support, we could have easily been buried throughout the entire day. Instead, we managed to emerge as #13 and continued to climb the ranks, demonstrating the power of an engaged community in driving a product’s growth.</span></p>
<h2>Launch Stats</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">On launch day, we coincidentally acquired exactly 100 new users, and with additional sign-ups in the following week, we reached a total of 230 new users. Among these, 9 converted to paid users, resulting in a conversion rate of approximately 4%.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image--wide"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/51c6586b-c80c-4083-89b8-c74fc800a3c2_720x402.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/51c6586b-c80c-4083-89b8-c74fc800a3c2_720x402-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/51c6586b-c80c-4083-89b8-c74fc800a3c2_720x402-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/51c6586b-c80c-4083-89b8-c74fc800a3c2_720x402-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/44/responsive/51c6586b-c80c-4083-89b8-c74fc800a3c2_720x402-lg.png 1024w"  alt="" width="720" height="402"></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite feeling as though we were deprived of the #1 position, it's important to remember that a launch is not a sprint but a marathon. In the grand scheme of things, a year from now, this minor setback won't even matter the slightest. If someone is meant to become our user, we will undoubtedly cross paths with them eventually — we just have to keep going to meet them. </span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Typogram Product Updates: Extra Icons</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://typogram.co/blog/typogram-product-updates-no10/"/>
        <id>https://typogram.co/blog/typogram-product-updates-no10/</id>
            <category term="Startups"/>
            <category term="Inside Typogram"/>

        <updated>2023-09-07T18:06:13-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/43/productUpate10.png" alt="Typogram Product Updates, No.10" />
                    How is Typogram development going? Since our last update, we have been&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/43/productUpate10.png" alt="Typogram Product Updates, No.10" />
                <blockquote>
<p><strong>How is Typogram development going?</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Since our last update, we have been busy implementing features and changes per your feedback and suggestions. Here are the new features we have in the pipeline! </p>
<hr>
<h1>Upcoming New Feature: Extra Icons</h1>
<p>A popular user request is adding extra icons next to the brand name. We are excited to announce an upcoming new feature, Extra Icons, which allows you to add icons next to the brand name text on the canvas. We are incredibly proud of this feature because it required overcoming significant technical challenges. We worked tirelessly to ensure that the design process remains smooth and intuitive for users while also allowing for the flexibility and customization options that Extra Icons provides.</p>
<p>With Extra Icons, you also can readjust the position of the text and icon independently and recenter them on canvas. This new feature gives you complete control over your logo’s layout, allowing you to create the perfect balance and visual impact. It will help you take your branding to the next level and express your creativity in new and exciting ways.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/lYqRJZYKHhe-SCFna79Q-BSIw4560soMTqAJB3xWjjWXMgTUcFFtP8kEFJbdjkzmB0wfacyftj-cudFU1Md4349PcyBf-Ko66MBSnxQ1LLOwX1cuNwavE3q6OJMWh_Z3PMXJljMb6B-s_jYP6pfnj3E" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/lYqRJZYKHhe-SCFna79Q-BSIw4560soMTqAJB3xWjjWXMgTUcFFtP8kEFJbdjkzmB0wfacyftj-cudFU1Md4349PcyBf-Ko66MBSnxQ1LLOwX1cuNwavE3q6OJMWh_Z3PMXJljMb6B-s_jYP6pfnj3E"><figcaption>Extra Icons in action!</figcaption></figure>
<h1> </h1>
<h1>Introducing Typogram Help Center</h1>
<p>We launched <a target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" href="https://typogram.co/help/">Typogram Help Center</a>, a resource center for questions and how-tos for our logo design tool. We have written posts on common questions, like how to change brand name, and helpful design tutorials, like using grid view and duplicated artboard to create iterations. We have more posts on the way!</p>
<p>Another popular request is embedding short, how-to videos highlighting features inside the app –– we are currently working on this. Mini Videos for Brand Personality, Brand Color, Kerning, and Distinctive Logos are launching soon!</p>
<figure class="Img: Check out Typogram Help Center!" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://buttondown.imgix.net/images/a96cb4bc-9cfa-4c02-b136-d4203d49789b.png?w=960&amp;fit=max" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Check out Typogram Help Center!"></figure>
<figcaption >Check out <a target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" href="https://typogram.co/help/">Typogram Help Center!</a></figcaption>
</figure>
<h1>Hearing More from You</h1>
<p>We’d love to hear more of your thoughts if you have already tried the software. Please share them with us by directly replying to this email or filling out this <a href="https://jbdpbt92.r.us-east-1.awstrack.me/L0/https:%2F%2Ftally.so%2Fr%2FmVGEQv/1/0100018776e370c2-29c8d886-39e7-4120-94f4-168d782109c8-000000/Irlaysx-uaFbaRff3AY8sSOUrzQ=317" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://jbdpbt92.r.us-east-1.awstrack.me/L0/https:%252F%252Ftally.so%252Fr%252FmVGEQv/1/0100018776e370c2-29c8d886-39e7-4120-94f4-168d782109c8-000000/Irlaysx-uaFbaRff3AY8sSOUrzQ%3D317&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1681420341381000&amp;usg=AOvVaw2HdaAikD0_rnxRQNIiOEZw">very short feedback form</a>. If you haven’t tried, we encourage you to create an account and use the Free Trial to play with the tool.</p>
<p>If you encounter any issues, please help us improve by reporting the issue from inside the app or directly through <a href="https://jbdpbt92.r.us-east-1.awstrack.me/L0/https:%2F%2Ftally.so%2Fr%2FmOQxJ7/1/0100018776e370c2-29c8d886-39e7-4120-94f4-168d782109c8-000000/jt5bbVq2yHnitPeKNdaIDzDB-1I=317" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" target="_blank" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://jbdpbt92.r.us-east-1.awstrack.me/L0/https:%252F%252Ftally.so%252Fr%252FmOQxJ7/1/0100018776e370c2-29c8d886-39e7-4120-94f4-168d782109c8-000000/jt5bbVq2yHnitPeKNdaIDzDB-1I%3D317&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1681420341381000&amp;usg=AOvVaw0uDcxTRvJozsEQU6M5D9b6">here</a>. You can also chat with us via the chat window inside the app. We are online during the daytime in the EST time zone (and some night time too).</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Typogram Product Updates: Case Switching &amp; Tool Tips</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://typogram.co/blog/typogram-product-updates-no9/"/>
        <id>https://typogram.co/blog/typogram-product-updates-no9/</id>
            <category term="Startups"/>
            <category term="Inside Typogram"/>

        <updated>2023-06-18T05:05:50-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/42/update9Cover.png" alt="" />
                    If you enjoyed this post, subscribe to get updates from our blog!&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/42/update9Cover.png" alt="" />
                <form action="https://buttondown.email/api/emails/embed-subscribe/typogramco" method="post" target="popupwindow">
<p align="center"><em>If you enjoyed this post, subscribe to get updates from our blog! </em></p>
<p align="center"><input id="bd-email" class="bd-email" name="email" type="email" placeholder="Enter your email"> <input class="bd-submit" type="submit" value="Subscribe"></p>
</form><hr>
<blockquote><strong>How is Typogram development going?</strong></blockquote>
<p>We hope Spring has been treating you nicely so far. Thanks again for your support! (Missed the previous updates? See our <a href="https://typogram.co/blog/typogram-product-updates-no8/">last update</a> and our archive <a href="https://typogram.co/blog/tags/inside-typogram/">here</a>).</p>
<p>Since our launch a few weeks ago, we have been getting many fantastic feedbacks and working on bug fixes and new features accordingly. We’d love to hear more of your thoughts if you have already tried the tool. Please share them with us by directly replying to this email or filling out this <a href="https://tally.so/r/mVGEQv">very short feedback form</a>. If you haven’t tried, we encourage you to create an account and use the Free Trial to play with our product!</p>
<hr>
<h1 id="new-feature-1-case-switching">New Feature No.1: Case Switching</h1>
<p>Currently, our app offers a lifetime brand license, which we enforce by locking the brand name. Once the brand project is created, users can’t edit the brand name independently and must contact us. A few users requested a brand name change to explore capitalizing certain letters in their logo. This limitation is not what I intended — locking the brand name shouldn’t prevent users from switching the letter case. So I immediately started designing and implementing this feature. This feature is available in this app right now!</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/ZA71yxgxQ59XQ0jcCugCd0o2dzQWICX7-ViWm7O0XBN3uNOxeo0T7BYSDDDBrcyeb3UrSJn_1AHtQs9-uJV2sc5WKd3FKJx4IS10PTaioTDR5_jK6qkMfMgUa8E44L3d-o2pVDxzkZXlcuIWu2EqLWk" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="caseSwitch"><figcaption>Switch letter case</figcaption></figure>
<h1> </h1>
<h1 id="new-feature-2-tool-tips">New Feature No.2: Tool Tips</h1>
<p>Another feedback I received was about progression. Users often have to perform specific actions inside our app before the “Continue” button appears, allowing them to progress to the next step. It is not uncommon for users to get confused about how to move forward before the “Continue” button appears for the first time. To help solve this issue, I added a disabled state of the Continue button and tooltips.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/z8Rk7d_LfO_xMkju3NRafayPJEdRqzOS6yDbskSpfD0AGbhEQRcphzgqYXKrkh1tLz7mdF3XbpWRk6Nu1Bjf9AZ-X_1V2bcTHg3c3XqrHrDcIqUUaRLgt_X72wtd2o8M5WnPl1B7VoQqok12XevqbPA" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Tooltip"><figcaption>Tool tip on Continue button</figcaption></figure>
<hr>
<h1 id="upcoming-new-feature-undoredo">Upcoming New Feature: Undo/Redo</h1>
<p>Undo and Redo are the most popular feature requests we have received since our launch, and we have been busy making them a reality. With the new Undo/Redo feature, if you made a mistake, or changed your mind regarding a design decision, you can click the Undo button to revert to the previous state. Similarly, if you liked the reverted changes, simply click Redo to reapply the design choices.</p>
<p>We added a cute micro interaction for your delight! The feature will be released very soon (after more testing). Stay tuned!</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/Inkhzt4oKMZGeb-L_SXYpIFsVYabTTh4n99bcGwobujqaX5-vM7rmoIxlQhlYHq_JerAWUxy-GonVHZ3_dMVo0OBQXFHSbticy3zpc1T3KcSBbINsGQO-LbfEqzvGsQTyvQeVRLeYANghdpJcCJpiWI" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Undo"><figcaption>Undo and redo</figcaption></figure>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/roY6idE1sliDt-uI4ChFHZF3_YgPnN_Mpsv9itFphbRLyBT7wQPPP9ZdOWM_t2Fe_NWv3cSIjBWpFdnOfVz5XumH5WK9EkGTdF0jTCC6NP-sxcMvxx6tLwpICh11tW9N1uqayY4U2L0B72wcb42t2lc" data-is-external-image="true"  alt="Micro interaction with the undo / redo buttons" width="172" height="84"></figure>
<figcaption >Micro interaction with the undo / redo buttons</figcaption>
</figure>
<hr>
<h1 id="we-want-to-hear-more">Hearing More</h1>
<p>We love critical feedback and can’t wait to hear your thoughts on the tool. If you encounter any issues, please help us improve by reporting the issue from inside the app or directly through <a href="https://tally.so/r/mOQxJ7">here</a>. Additionally, you can also chat with us via the chat window inside the app. We are online during the daytime in the EST time zone (and some night time too). If you have any questions, feedback, or comments, just hit reply! We love to hear from you!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Font Details You Must Know to Improve Your Designs</title>
        <author>
            <name>Wenting Zhang</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://typogram.co/blog/font-details-you-must-know-to-improve-your-designs/"/>
        <id>https://typogram.co/blog/font-details-you-must-know-to-improve-your-designs/</id>
            <category term="Typography &amp; Fonts"/>

        <updated>2023-07-24T18:41:17-04:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/typeDetailsCover-2.png" alt="" />
                    We are continuing our Typography Jargon Buster series! This time, we go&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/typeDetailsCover-2.png" alt="" />
                <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We are continuing our <em>Typography Jargon Buster</em> series! This time, we go over type detail terms describing constructions of letters. These visual elements make fonts different from each other to communicate different meanings. </span></p>
<p><em><span style="font-weight: 400;">Want to read more Typography Jargon Buster? Check out <a href="https://typogram.co/blog/essential-terms-you-must-know-about-typography/">Essential Typography Terms</a>, <a href="https://typogram.co/blog/common-styles-of-serif-fonts-you-must-know-to-improve-your-design/">Serif</a>, and <a href="https://typogram.co/blog/different-types-of-sans-serifs/">Sans Serifs Classifications You Must Know.</a></span></em></p>
<h1> </h1>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Ascender</span><a id="Ascender"></a></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">An ascender is a vertical stroke of a lowercase letter extending upwards, beyond the x-height, sometimes beyond the cap height. For example, “h” is a lowercase letter with an ascender. In general, typefaces having long ascenders and descenders help with readability. Long ascenders help make a lowercase more distinguishable as long as the other parts of the letters are legible.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/ascender-3.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/ascender-3-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/ascender-3-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/ascender-3-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/ascender-3-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Ascender" width="1200" height="630"></figure>
<h1> </h1>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Baseline</span><a id="Baseline"></a></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The baseline is the horizon line (sometimes invisible) on which the letters sit. In most typefaces, curved letters, like “O,” “e,” and “s,” sit slightly below the baseline to create optical balance and alignment with other letters. Letters with descenders like “p” and “q” extend below the baseline.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/baseline-3.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/baseline-3-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/baseline-3-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/baseline-3-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/baseline-3-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Baseline" width="1200" height="630"></figure>
<h1> </h1>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bracket</span><a id="Bracket"></a></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A bracket is a curved or wedge-like area connecting a serif and a stroke. This curve area can be large or small. Typefaces with large areas of curves are said to have large bracketing. Those with small curved areas have small bracketing. Some serif typefaces have no bracketing. </span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/bracket-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/bracket-2-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/bracket-2-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/bracket-2-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/bracket-2-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Bracket" width="1200" height="630"></figure>
<h1> </h1>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cap Height</span><a id="CapHeight"></a></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cap Height is the height of a capital letter, measured from the baseline to flat capitals like “H.” Letters like “S” and “O,” have a slight overshoot over the cap height. This is done so that curve-topped letters like “S” or “O” look optically aligned and balanced with flat-topped letters like “H.”</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/cap-height-3.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/cap-height-3-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/cap-height-3-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/cap-height-3-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/cap-height-3-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Cap Height" width="1200" height="630"></figure>
<h1> </h1>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Counter</span><a id="Counter"></a></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A counter is an unfilled (white or negative) space partially or entirely closed by other parts of the letters. For example, lowercase “b” and uppercase “U” both have counters. The stroke creating a counter shape is known as a “bowl.” There are two types of counter spaces: open and closed. An <strong>open counter</strong> means the unfilled space is partially closed, like “U.” A <strong>closed counter</strong> happens when the unfilled space is completely sealed, like “b.” </span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/counter.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/counter-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/counter-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/counter-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/counter-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Counter" width="1200" height="630"></figure>
<h1> </h1>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Descender</span><a id="Descender"></a></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A descender is a vertical stroke of a lowercase letter extending below the baseline. For example, “p” is a lowercase letter with a descender. Like ascenders, long descenders make lowercase letters more distinguishable, improving readability.  </span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/descender-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/descender-2-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/descender-2-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/descender-2-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/descender-2-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Descender" width="1200" height="630"></figure>
<h1> </h1>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">Terminal</span><a id="Terminal"></a></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A Terminal is an end of a straight or curved stroke without serifs. The terminal can be a place where a typeface showcases its stylistic elements. For example, in some letters, like “a,” there can be a droplet shape at the end of a stroke. This is called a ball terminal. </span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/ball-terminal.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/ball-terminal-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/ball-terminal-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/ball-terminal-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/ball-terminal-lg.png 1024w"  alt="Terminal" width="1200" height="630"></figure>
<h1> </h1>
<h1><span style="font-weight: 400;">x-Height</span><a id="x-Height"></a></h1>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The term x-height describes the distance from the baseline to the top of a flat-topped lowercase letter, like the lowercase “x.” x-height is a stylistic choice and varies for different typefaces. However, x-height also is a factor in readability. As the x-height increase, the length of ascenders and descenders usually decreases. This causes the letters to become less readable.</span></p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/x-height-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/x-height-2-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/x-height-2-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/x-height-2-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/x-height-2-lg.png 1024w"  alt="x-Height" width="1200" height="630"></figure>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/typedetails.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/typedetails-xs.png 300w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/typedetails-sm.png 480w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/typedetails-md.png 768w ,https://typogram.co/blog/media/posts/40/responsive/typedetails-lg.png 1024w"  alt="type details" width="1680" height="630">
<figcaption >Infographic summing up type detail terms</figcaption>
</figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Want more Typography Jargon Buster?</strong> Check out <a href="https://typogram.co/blog/essential-terms-you-must-know-about-typography/"><em>Essential Typography Terms</em></a>, <em><a href="https://typogram.co/blog/common-styles-of-serif-fonts-you-must-know-to-improve-your-design/">Serif</a></em>, and <em><a href="https://typogram.co/blog/different-types-of-sans-serifs/">Sans Serifs Classifications You Must Know.</a></em></span></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
